(シズネ)綱手様。
(綱手)なんだ？
Lady Tsunade?
What is it?
今日は一度も
お食事をなさっていませんが…。
You haven't eaten at all today.
Oh, I didn't realize
it was this late.
(綱手)ああ… もうこんな時間か。
Is that work?
(シズネ)お仕事ですか？
No. Just Jiraiya's silly novel.
いや 自来也の くだらない小説だ。
Oh…you mean
the "Make Out" series…
ああ あのイチャイチャとかいうシリーズの。
Actually, no.
This one's a little different.
それがな 今度のはちょっと違う。
ナルトやサスケたち➡
It's about Naruto, Sasuke,
and the young generation of the Leaf.
木ノ葉の
若い世代のことを描いた→
It's actually a good read…
結構 まじめな内容で➡
つい読みふけってしまった。
I can't put it down.
Really?
そうでしたか。 ところで➡
Anyway, what would you like
to do about dinner?
夕食はどうなさいますか？
今 いいところなんだ。
I'm at a really good part right now…
Shall I have dinner brought to you?
お食事 こちらに運びましょうか？
Oh, I'd appreciate that.
そうか。 そうしてくれると助かる。
はい。 では 早速…。
All right,
it will be just a moment.
どれどれ…
どこまで読んだっけな？
Okay…where was I?
How do you know about my father?
(ネジ)貴様は
なぜ父上のことを知っている？
(ネジ)なぜ 木ノ葉隠れの掟を
変えようというのだ。
Why would someone like you,
from another village,
want us to change
the laws of the Hidden Leaf?
Our dissatisfaction is common
throughout the Shinobi World.
我々の無念さは
忍の世に共通のもの。
If we first change
the Five Great Nations
まずは 五大里 最大の
木ノ葉隠れを変えれば➡
and its most influential village,
the Hidden Leaf,
the entire Shinobi World will change.
いずれ忍世界 全体が
変わることになる。
貴様なら そんな
木ノ葉隠れの里の掟を➡
Are you telling me
you can change the laws
of a village as great
as Hidden Leaf Village?
変えられるというのか。
ああ。
Yes… And that is why I want
collaborators who will cooperate.
そのために 協力者が欲しいのだ。
《やつらか》
Is it them?
お前だけでもいい ついてこい。
You will suffice…
Follow me!
わかった。
All right.
(ナルト)ネジ 行くな！
Neji! Don't go!
ここで待っていろ。
Wait here. I'm just going to
hear what he has to say.
話を聞くだけだ。
ダメだ。 行かせねえってばよ！
No! I won't let you go!
くっ…。
You just aimed for Chakra Points
that would paralyze.
体の動きを止める
点穴を突いたな。
Yes. His life isn't in danger.
ああ… だが 命に危険はない。
しばらくの間 我慢していてくれ。
Hang in there for just a while.
やつの目論見を確かめたら
必ず 戻ってくる。
I want to see what he's planning,
then I promise I'll be back.
ネ… ジ…。
N-Neji…
Jiraiya Ninja Scrolls:
The Tale of Naruto the Hero-
The Sealed Power
気にするな！
No need to worry about them.
They share my views.
私と 志をひとつにする者。
We would like to present
our report…
(弥彦)報告しておきたいことが…。
幼い兄弟を巻き込んだ
あの騒ぎのことか？
Is this about the disturbance
involving the young siblings?
ああ。
Yes…
木ノ葉の下忍たちとの
戦闘中に起こった➡
This is in regard to
the cave-in that occurred
崩落事故のことだ。
while we were fighting
a few of the Leaf Genin.
(長門)一事は 地下に巣くっていた
怪物に襲われ➡
At one point, a monster that
was nesting underground
あの子らの命も
危ういところだった。
endangered the kids' lives.
(小南)木ノ葉の下忍たちは
非情にも➡
For a time,
the Leaf Genin coldly put
their mission first and left.
一度は 任務を優先し立ち去った。
《木ノ葉の下忍？》
Leaf Genin?
掟という呪縛が→
So the accursed laws
have found their way
若き世代にまで
しみ込んでいるというのだな？
deep into the hearts
of the younger generation…
違うんだ。
ん？
But it hasn't.
やつらは あのあと戻ってきた。
They returned soon after
何のゆかりもない俺たちと→
to rescue the children, and us
even though they had no ties…
村の子供を助けるために。
(長門)彼らは
いいやつでした。
They were good people.
(小南)少なくとも
あの瞬間は…。
At least, at that moment they were…
I feel they can become a force
(弥彦)彼らは きっと忍の未来を
揺り動かす力になりえる。
that will rouse the future
of shinobi.
As for the Hidden Leaf
as an organization,
もっとも 木ノ葉隠れという
集団になったとき➡
どう動くか 更に確かめる
必要があるかもしれないが。
we'll probably have to see
how they make their move.
ご苦労だった。
Good work.
I want you to continue
your surveillance.
引き続き 監視を続けろ。
That incident you were speaking of…
今の話 あれは
俺たちの仲間のことか？
Was it about my fellow genin
from the Leaf?
ああ。
Yes…
What is your objective?!
貴様の目的は何だ？
何を確かめようとしているんだ？
What are you trying to confirm?
お前も ともに確かめてみないか？
Would you like to find out with me?
あの男が言ったように➡
Like that man said…
やつらが 忍の未来を揺り動かす
力になりえるか どうかを。
To see if those genin
can become a force…
that can rouse the future of shinobi?
クッソ～！
D-Damn it!
《点穴だか何だか知んねえが➡
Chakra Points or whatever…
身動きひとつできねえなんて
情けねえ！
It's sad that I can't move!
もし もっとチャクラがあれば→
If only I had more chakra,
a jutsu like this would be easy to…
きっとこんな術なんか…
父ちゃん》
Dad.
I've got this thing called
the Nine Tails sealed inside me…
((九尾なんか
封印されたおかげで→
俺ってば すげえ大変なんだぞ！
And this is a huge problem!
(ミナト)
ナルトいつか話したことがあるね。
Naruto…
I once told you, remember?
(ミナト)九尾を２つに分けて
その半分を母さんに残し➡
I split the Nine Tails in two and
left half inside your mother
and sealed the other half inside you.
And the reason was…
残り半分を
お前に封印した理由を。
うん 人柱力の母さんの命を
救うためだって。
Uh-huh… to save Mom's life,
because she's a Jinchuriki.
ああ。
Yes.
でも それだけじゃなかったんだ。
But that wasn't all.
えっ？
Huh?!
I sealed the other half of
the Nine Tails inside you
九尾の半分を封印したのは➡
キミならその力を使いこなせると
信じていたからなんだ。
because I had faith that you would be
able to master the use of its power.
あ…。
九尾のチャクラは お前にとって
おおいなる力になってくれる。
The Nine Tails' chakra will become
an immense power for you…
コントロールさえできればね。
as long as you can control it.
でも そんな力 何のために？
But what's the purpose…
of such a power?
いつか必ず
その力が必要になる。
One day, that power will
become necessary.
(本当に守りたい 大切な何かを
見つけられたら きっとね))
When you are able to find
something precious
that you really want to protect…
I guarantee it.
《その力を使い
俺が守りたい大切なもの…。
Something precious that I want
to protect with its power…
こら アホギツネ！
Hey, you dumb fox!
Lend me your chakra again!
またチャクラを貸しやがれ！
Use your chakra and turn
my Chakra Points back to normal!
お前のチャクラを使って
点穴を元に戻してくれ！》
どうした？
What's the matter?
なんで答えてくんねえんだ!?
九尾！
Why aren't you answering me,
Nine Tails?!
(サスケ)ここで アスマ班
紅班と合流しよう。
We'll rendezvous with Team Asuma
and Team Kurenai here.
ここなら感知しやすいはずだ。
This spot will be easy to sense.
(サクラ)でも…。
時間的に見て➡
But…
Considering the time,
紅班とアスマ班は
もう合流している頃。
Teams Asuma and Kurenai
have probably joined up.
次は 俺たちを捜すはずだ。
They should come
looking for us next.
Even if it's just the two of us,
私たち２人だけでも
里へ向かったほうがよくない？
shouldn't we head back
to the village?
四代目が この任務に
俺たちを選んだのは➡
Lord Fourth didn't choose us
for this mission
戦闘能力があると
判断してじゃない。
because of our fighting ability.
He chose us merely because
the younger we are,
若いほうが 今度の敵が使う術に
かかりにくいからにすぎない。
the harder it is for the enemy
to use their jutsu on us.
だから 状況がわかりしだい➡
That's why he ordered us to return
to the village immediately
戦わず すぐに里へ戻るように
命令したんだ。
without engaging as soon
as we scoped out the situation.
うん。
Oh.
敵の正体 人数がわからない以上➡
We still haven't identified the enemy
and don't know how many there are,
俺たちが戦力を
分散させるのはまずい。
so it's bad to divide up
our fighting power.
Then what about the others who
went to save their teammates?
じゃあ 仲間を助けようとして
行ってしまったみんなは？
A shinobi puts priority
on the rules…
忍が優先すべきは 掟。
そして 掟に基づく命令。
and the orders given
under the rules…
情に流されて動いてはダメなんだ。
We can't be swayed
by compassion.
Guy Sensei!
(リー)ガイ先生！ ネジ！
Neji!
Wait, Lee!
(テンテン)ちょっと待ちなさいよ リー！
What are you saying?
何を言ってるんです？
ガイ先生を見つけるんです。
We have to find Guy Sensei!
But searching blindly
like this isn't…
だから
そんな闇雲に捜したって…。
Blind or not,
I will find Guy Sensei!
闇だろうと雲だろうと
ガイ先生を見つけてみせます。
Are you okay?
大丈夫？
ガハッ。
しっかりして。
Get a hold of yourself!
くっ…。
え…。
うぅ。
What?
動いてないと不安で 怖くて➡
Unless I'm doing something,
I feel so uneasy and scared.
恐ろしいことばかり
考えてしまうんです。
And I end up thinking about all of
the bad things that can happen…
うぅ…。
お 落ち着いて。
Calm down…
Your perseverance
is sure to pay off!
リーの努力 きっと実るわ。
うっ そうですよね！
You're right!
いいんですよね！
努力あるのみですよね！
It's okay! All I have to do
is persevere!
うぉ～ ガイ先生 ネジ！
Guy Sensei! Neji!
(チョウジ)どうなの？ キバ。
Well, Kiba?!
(いの)みんなと合流できそう？
Will we be able to join up
with everyone?
(赤丸)ク～ン。
Lee's started running around again.
(キバ)リーのやつが
また走り出しやがった。
テンテンも一緒かな？
I wonder if Tenten's with him.
ああ リーの後ろを追いかけてる。
Yeah, she's right behind Lee.
(シカマル)同じ班とはいえ→
They're on the same team,
but she must be going crazy
trying to keep up with Lee.
リーに振り回されて
あいつも災難だな。
アハハ そうだね。
True.
(シノ)ネジはどうしてる？
ネジがいるなら➡
What's Neji doing?
If Neji's around, Lee won't be
able to do whatever he pleases.
リーも そうそう勝手な振る舞いも
できないはずだが。
なぜなら…。
それがよ➡
That's because…
The thing is…
ネジのニオイがしねえんだ。
I can't pick up on Neji's scent.
No, Neji is there…
(ヒナタ)いえ ネジ兄さんはいる。
Near Sasuke and Sakura.
サスケ君とサクラさんの近くに。
ネジは１人か？ ナルトは？
Is he alone? What about Naruto?
I don't see Naruto.
ナルト君の姿は見当たらないけど➡
But…how can I put this…
なんだろう… ネジ兄さんは
モヤモヤした中にいる感じ。
It feels like Neji is inside
something hazy…
And there's someone next
to him.
しかも 隣には誰かもう１人。
Are there any others?
他には誰かいねえか？
サスケ君とサクラさんの陰に
もう１人潜んでる！
There's someone else lurking around
Sakura and Sasuke!
Sasuke and Sakura are our comrades
from the Hidden Leaf.
サスケもサクラも
俺たち木ノ葉隠れの里の仲間だ。
その本性 見定めるがよい。
Then see for yourself
what they are really like.
サスケ君？
Sasuke?
黙ってろ。
Be quiet…
《もしかしてキバたち？》
Is it Kiba and the others?
《火遁 鳳仙火の術！》
Fire Style! Phoenix Flower Jutsu!
(ヒルコ)どうにも
じっとしていられない➡
I had you pegged as a brat who can't
stay still and loves to show off…
目立ちたがりのガキと見たが➡
まぁ 俺は待つのが嫌いだからな。
Oh well, I don't like to wait,
so I guess we can start this.
もう おっぱじめてもいいか。
貴様 何者だ！
Who the hell are you?
門番ってとこか。
You can think of me
as a gatekeeper.
貴様らを
これ以上 外へ出さないためのな。
I'm not letting you
go any further.
そうだな 俺たちには
ネジのニオイは感じらんねえけど➡
Yes… We can't smell Neji,
サスケの近くに
もう１人いるのは間違いねえ。
but there's no mistake that
there's another guy close to Sasuke.
If you can't smell him, how can he
be seen with the Byakugan?
ニオイは感じられないが
白眼で見えてるとは➡
どういうことだ？
理由はわからねえが➡
What does it mean?
I don't know, but it probably means
that the enemy is still detaining Neji.
ネジは まだその敵に
捕らえられてるってことだろう。
確かに ネジ兄さんは➡
There's no mistake…
Neji isn't trying to move out
of that haze.
そのモヤモヤの中から
動こうとはしていない。
なら ここにいても
しようがないんじゃない？
Then there's nothing
we can do by staying here.
ヒナタ 案内して。
(ヒナタ)任せて。
Hinata, lead the way.
You got it.
行くぞ。
Let's go!
うっとおしいハエだな。
Such annoying flies.
Want me to smash them
with my fly swatter?
俺のハエ叩きで
ぶっ叩いてやろうか。
尻尾の先端！
The tip of the tail
could be poisoned!
もしかして毒かもしれない。
フフフフ…。
ガイ先生！ ネジ！
Guy Sensei! Neji!
ナルト君と班長の皆さ～ん！
Naruto and the team captains!
どうしたの？
What's the matter?!
Tenten!
テンテン！
逃げるのよ！
Run!
やばい！
This is bad!
うわっ 何です!? うわ～っ！
What are they?
ガイ先生たちをさらったやつらに
違いありません。
They must be the ones
who abducted Guy Sensei!
何としても
捕まえてやりましょう。
We must capture them!
今は なんとか逃げて➡
We have to get away somehow,
and move to a more suitable place
for close combat.
近距離戦闘に適した場所に
出るしかないわ！
クッ！
ワン！ ワン！
あぁ 変だな。
Yeah, it's strange.
Lee and Tenten's movements
seem irregular.
リーたちの動きが普通じゃねえ。
どういうことだ？
What do you mean?!
偶然かもしれない。
It could be a coincidence,
けど リーさんたちは→
but Lee and the others are heading
to where Sasuke is fighting.
サスケ君たちの
戦闘現場に向かってる。
そりゃ 好都合だ。
That's perfect!
このまま突っ走るぞ！
Let's hurry over there too!
(ヒナタ)はい！
Right!
なめるなよ クナイがダメなら…。
Don't underestimate me…
If a kunai won't work…
火遁 豪火球の術！
Fire Style! Fireball Jutsu!
何なんだ こいつは…。
What the hell is he?
人間なの？
Is he human?
人間？
"Human…"?
フフフフ… そんな
つまんねえもんじゃねえよ。
俺の芸術だ。
サスケ君！
これって 毒が！
うっ…。
サスケ君！
《思わずやっちまった。
が １人殺したくらい
どうとでもなる》
《このアホギツネ！
どうして なんにも
答えてくんねえんだよ！》
《九喇嘛 : うるせえ》
《九尾》
今のお前にゃ
無理な相談だからだ。
何がだよ！
動きを止める点穴に施された
術を解き放つには➡
俺のチャクラを大量に
コントロールする必要がある。
でも 今のお前に
そんな芸当できやしないだろう。
なに～ やってみなくちゃ
わかんねえだろ！
ほう 悔しかったら
まずは八卦封印の鍵を開けて➡
俺を自由にしてみろ。
そしたら考えてやるさ。
《父ちゃんの八卦封印を？
そんなこと 今の俺にはできねえ》
(自来也)口寄せ 蝦蟇口縛り。
エロ仙人!?
皆様 お変わりございませんか？
美空ひばりです。
今日も
皆さんに喜んでいただける歌を➡
選んだつもりです。
どうぞ最後まで
ごゆっくりご覧ください。
＜オープニングを飾るのは➡
おおらかな気持にしてくれる
名曲です＞